RESUME

AJABRAO DIGAMBAR KUTE

Mr Ajabrao Kute Flat no 403,Sai estate, Silicon City, Indore, India Email: <u>ajabkute3@gmail.com</u>; Phone: +91- 8668359276

Gender: Male; Citizen of India DOB: 3rd February 1989

Career Summary

I am a postgraduate with over 8+ years of experience in the field of Quality control Microbiology. To achieve a challenging and meaningful position in an elite organization where my skills, knowledge and interpersonal skills will effectively synergized in the exponential growth of the organization. Wish to build up my career by playing a vital role in the Pharmaceuticals industry.

Education

- M.Sc. Microbiology 72.47 (Sant Gadge Baba Amravati University, Amravati, 2011)
- **B. Sc. Microbiology 61** % (Shree Shivaji Science College, Chikhali, 2009)
- HSC 58.67 % (Shree Shivaji Science College, Chikhali, 2006)
- SSC 69.33% (Surybhan Bapu Khedekar Vidhyalay, Khairao, 2004)

Professional Experience

- Officer (QC Microbiology, Lupin Ltd. Pithampur . May 2020– Present)
- **Sr. Executive** (QC Microbiology, Cipla Ltd. Goa. Dec 2018– May 2020)
- **Research Associate R-3** (Microbiology Department, Wockhardt Research Centre, Aurangabad, Jan.2015– Dec.2018)
- Industrial Trainee (Microbiology Department, Wockhardt Research Centre, Aurangabad, Oct.2014

 –Jan 2015)
- Project Fellow (Microbiology Department, SGBAU Amaravati, Nov 2012– June 2014

Skills

- Performing Sterility analysis and Method Validation for Raw Material, Finish products and packing material.
- BET testing for finish product, raw material, and WFI and method validation.
- Trend preparation, Investigation of incidence and Change control.
- Prepare, review and update SOP, protocols related to microbiological testing.
- Bio-burden analysis, GPT and swab analysis, Release and transfer of MLT, water, EM, GPT, sterility.
- Performing Microbial Limit Test for Finished and Raw materials as well as method validation.
- Water analysis for WFI, Purified water and potable water.
- Handling of cultures, sub culturing and enrichment of isolated cultures.
- Calibration of weighing balances and pH meter, Media preparation.
- Environmental monitoring of active, passive, surface and personnel monitoring.
- Particulate matter test and liquid borne particle counter test for ophthalmic product.

- In-house isolates identification through analytical profile index (API) and VITEK MS (MALDI_TOF).
- Review and observation of Water analysis, MLT, Environmental monitoring, GPT, BET, Sterility and BL
- Requalification of equipment and instrument, Vendor follow up and PR creation.
- Proficiency in Laboratory Information Management System (LIMS), SABA, SAP.
- Audit faced USFDA, MHRA, EU, WHO, third party and internal audit.

Computer Proficiency

Maharashtra State - Certificate in Information Technology (2006)

Efficiency

- Professional and proactive approach with strong work ethics towards the assigned job.
- Good writing and verbal communication skills in English.
- Ability to manage competing priorities effectively.
- Excellent organizational and problem solving skills.

Declaration:

I hereby declare that the details furnished above are true and correct to the best of my knowledge.

Date:	Yours Faithfully
Sign:	Mr. Aiabrao D. Kute